# JOHN JANG

#### **Product Designer**

iscolbe9675@gmail.com

My portfolio

## **SUMMARY**

A Product Designer, graduated from York University, with over a year of professional experience in crafting user experience that suits the branding and another year of experience in web development. I am proficient in designing products from scratch till the launch, while considering the development perspective such as the User Interface development, CI/CD pipeline, deployment, etc. My strengths include strategic designing, initiating projects, and leading communications with internal and external teams. By nature, I am analytical, perceptive, and enjoy problem-solving. Outside of work, I am a runner, dancer, and a potential traveler.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

#### Product Designer

**OperateEase** 

08 / 2024 ~ Present | Remote, Toronto

- Developed a comprehensive design system to standardize UI components and hosted UX Design workshops to align with stakeholders and gather insights from users
- Led the design of an inventory management system, optimizing room occupancy and supply management, increasing efficiency by 60%

Collaborated closely with engineering teams to ensure design feasibility and maintain a high standard of quality

#### Product Designer Intern

The Sakhi

06 / 2024  $\sim$  10 / 2024 | Remote, Toronto

 Conducted regular design critique sessions with Shopify developers to refine features and functionality based on feedback

# **UX** Designer

**TuGo Travel** 

03 / 2024 ~ 05 / 2024 | Remote, Toronto

UX/UI Design Apprentice TeleVU Innovation

06 / 2022 ~ 08 / 2022 | Remote, Toronto

### VOLUNTEER

# Web Development Apprentice Tech Fleet Professional Association

08 / 2023 ~ 09 / 2024 | Remote, Toronto

 Collaborated with UX designers to develop user-friendly applications, ensuring design integrity alongside development teams

# UX/UI Design Apprentice

**Tech Fleet Professional Association** 

04 / 2023 ~ 07 / 2023 | Remote, Toronto

 Designed and implemented a location-based, user-friendly search functionality serving over 5,000 users monthly

#### **EDUCATION**

**UX** Design

York University

North York, Ontario

Web Development Bootcamp

**Dream Coding Academy** 

Remote, Toronto

Psychology & Neuroscience

**University of New Brunswick** 

Fredericton, NB

#### **TOOLS & SKILLS**

Figma, Figjam, Miro, Wireframing, Sketching, Typography, Prototyping, Mock-ups, A/B Testing, Usability Testing Waterfall, User-Interface Design, User Research HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, TypeScript, Next.js, React, Vite, MongoDB, Express.js, Axios

#### OTHER LINKS

<u>LinkedIn - John Jang</u>

<u>My Web Development Portfolio</u>

<u>My Github Profile</u>